What is Python? Python is a general-purpose
language with a wide variety of uses, including
for basic apps, web development, data analysis,
artificial intelligence, the Internet of Things,
automation, and the topic we will use to teach
the concepts in this course: game development.
Take a look at this example of Python code. Python
code is known for being more natural-looking than
some other languages, namely Java, JavaScript,
and C#. We do not see curly brackets here as we
do in other languages. However, and this will be
emphasized throughout the course, Python is big
on indentation. For one example, notice the code
inside this if statement: it is indented. If the
code is not indented properly, it will not work.
The more practice you get in recognizing when code
needs to be indented, the easier it will be to
determine when code needs to be indented. Python
is also an interpreted language, which means you
can write code and run it in the Python engine,
as opposed to a compiled language, such as C#,
which needs to be compiled into an executable or
similar file before it can be run. We also do not
need to worry about memory management in Python as
in other programming languages. Python is one
of many object-oriented programming languages
in that classes can be created, and objects can be
built within those classes. Classes are beyond the
scope of this exam, but know that they do exist.
Python is also a dynamically typed language,
meaning that data types do not need to be declared
on variables before the variables themselves are
declared. While on the subject of data types,
operations with data types and operators is
the first exam objective set in this course, so
let’s learn about those data types and operators.